让我们继续讨论视觉感受。其中一件事
Let’s continue our discussion about the sense of vision. One of the things that makes
视觉这样一个强大的传感器是它是一个远程传感器。它让我们感受到
vision such a powerful sensor is that it is a long-range sensor. It allows us to sense
超越我们指尖的世界。我们的指尖，我们的手臂只允许我们到达和探索
the world beyond our fingertips. Our fingertips, our arms only allow us to reach and explore
我们周围空间的一小部分。但有时候最重要的
a relatively small part of the space that is around us. But sometimes the most important
我们需要知道的事情远远超出我们指尖的范围;通过
things that we need to know about are far beyond the reach of our fingertips; by the
时间紧密的事情可能已经太晚了，所以视觉让我们看到了几十个
time things are that close it is perhaps too late, so vision allows us to see for tens
米，几百米，一个非常大的距离，这是一个非常大的美德
of meters, hundreds of meters, a very great distance and that is a really big virtue of
视觉感。感觉的另一个重要特征
the sense of vision. Another important characteristic of a sense
愿景是它提供了非常丰富的信息。我们知道一些事情
of vision is that it provides a very rich amount of information. We know something about
对象的形状，我们知道对象的颜色和形状
the shape of the object, we know something about the colour of the object, and that shape
除了纹理之外，还有颜色允许我们对对象进行分类以确定哪种类型
and colour in addition to texture allows us to classify the object to work out what sort
事情就是这样。这是我们感兴趣的事情吗？这是我们想要的
of thing it is. Is it a thing that we are interested in? Is it something we want to
逃避？或者我们想走向？它是什么类型的对象，这绝对是
run away from? Or we want to move towards? What sort of object it is, and that is absolutely
对于人们和机器人的许多，许多应用来说都是至关重要的。
critical for many, many applications for people and also for robots.
视觉的另一个巨大优势是它为我们提供了有关运动的信息，它告诉我们
Another great advantage of vision is it gives us information about motion and it tells us
关于事物如何在我们周围移动，所以我们可以看到一个物体，我们可以看到它在移动。
about how things are moving around us, so we can see an object and we can see it moving.
它离我们越来越近了，它会走得更远吗？但它也提供了大量信息
Is it getting closer to us, is it going further away? But it also provides a lot of information
关于我们如何移动，所以当我们走遍世界时，其他事情似乎已经过去了
about how we are moving, so as we walk through the world other things appear to move past
我们由于我们自己的议案。这么多动物使用视觉和视觉的事实
us due to our own motion. The fact that so many animals use vision and
在地球上，视觉感已经多次独立演变，
that the sense of vision has evolved independently multiple times here on planet earth argue,
我认为，对于视觉的有效性。几乎所有动物我们都使用
I think, for the effectiveness of the sense of vision. For almost all animals we use the
生命中真正重要的事物的视觉感。我们用它来帮助我们找到食物，我们
sense of vision for the really important things in life. We use it to help us find food, we
用它来避免被其他动物吃掉，我们用它来寻找我们的伴侣。所以所有的
use it to avoid being eaten by other animals and we use it to find our mates. So all the
重要的生命功能是通过视觉来调节的。
important life functions are mediated through the sense of vision.
看看由各种不同的动物做的这些任务。考虑
Have a look at these tasks being preformed by a variety of different animals. Consider
蜜蜂和蜜蜂是一种小动物，脑部非常小，但它有两只眼睛。
the bee, and a bee is a small animal, with a very small brain, but it has got two eyes.
相当复杂的眼睛，与我们的眼睛非常不同，但它可以表现得相当复杂
Quite complex eyes, very different sorts of eyes to ours, but it can perform quite complicated
功能。它可以飞行很长的距离，以便找到一些其他的花
functions. It can fly for a long distance in order to locate some flowers that other
蜜蜂已经告知了它。它可以落在移动的花朵上，也可以分辨出它
bees have informed it about. It can land on a moving flower or it can tell the difference
在一朵花和一片叶子之间。因此非常复杂的功能对蜜蜂的生命至关重要
between a flower and a leaf. So quite complex functions critical to the life of the bee
它的集落基本上是用视觉进行的。
and its colony are performed essentially using vision.
在中间，我们有人接球。他们用眼睛去抓住
In the middle, we have somebody catching a ball. They are using their eyes to catch the
球。他们没有使用GPS或任何其他类型的技术传感器。这个人
ball. They are not using GPS or any other kind of technological sensor. This person
他们把目光投向球，这是一个非常着名的表达方式。看着
has got their eyes on the ball and that is a very well-known expression. Watching the
球在空中移动时，他们有一些关于如何的心理模型
ball as it moves through the air and they have got some sort of mental model about how
球在空中移动。然后，他们正在使用它来计划他们的手应该如何
balls move through the air. They are using that, then, to plan how their hands should
移动是为了成功掌握球权。所以我们用眼睛去感知
move in order to achieve a successful grasp of the ball. So we are using our eyes to sense
球。我们正在制定计划，然后我们正在采取行动，我们正在动手以拦截它。
the ball. We are making a plan and then we are acting, we are moving our hands in order to intercept it.
最后一个例子是驾驶，我们用眼睛观察道路，人们
And the last example is driving, where we are using our eyes to observe the road, people
和正在路上行驶的汽车。我们已经知道了我们想要去的地方。
and cars that are moving on the road. We’ve got an idea of where it is we want to go.
因此，我们正在使用视觉信息，并考虑到目标。我们正在制定计划
So we are using the visual information with a goal in mind. We are making a plan about
如何沿着这条路走下去，然后我们通过转动
how to navigate down this particular bit of road and then we are acting by turning the
方向盘，踩刹车踏板或加速器。
steering wheel, pushing the brake pedal or the accelerator.